Lilian de Greef

Seattle, WA 98195 Idegreef@uw.edu

SUMMARY

I am a PhD student at the University of Washington with an NSF fellowship and Microsoft Research PhD fellowship, advised by Shwetak Patel in the Ubiquitous Computing Lab. Within the broad spectrum of ubiquitous computing, my interests include computer vision, embedded systems, machine learning, and HCI. My current research focuses on lowering the access barrier to medical care, using low cost commodity hardware with trained image analysis and innovative user interface design.

EDUCATION

University of Washington

9/2012 - present

Ph.D. Student, Computer Science Area: Ubiquitous Computing Advisor: Dr. Shwetak Patel

Harvey Mudd College

8/2008 - 5/2012

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Graduated with distinction

GPA: 3.6/4.0

HONORS AND AWARDS

- National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship: 2013 present
- Microsoft Research PhD Fellowship: 2015 2017
- Microsoft Research Graduate Women's Scholar: 2013 2014
- Marilyn Fries Endowed Regental Fellowship: 2012 2013
- President Scholar's Program (4 year full-tuition merit scholarship): 2008 2012
- University of Washington CSE Three-Sixty Fellowship Fund: 2012
- People's Choice Prize at UW CSE's Industry Affiliates Meeting: 2014
- Graduated Harvey Mudd College with honors in computer science: 2012
- Graduated Harvey Mudd College with honors in humanities, social sciences, and the arts: 2012
- Dean's List: Spring 2009, Fall 2009, Fall 2010, Fall 2011, Spring 2012

PUBLICATIONS

Taylor, J.A., Stout, J.W., **de Greef, L**., Goel, M., Patel, S., Chung, E.K., Koduri, A., McMahon, S., Dickerson, J., Simpson, E.A. and Larson, E.C., 2017. *Use of a Smartphone App to Assess Neonatal Jaundice.* Pediatrics, p.e20170312.



de Greef, L., Goel, M., Seo, M.J., Larson, E.C., Patel, S.N., Stout, J.W., Taylor, J.A. *BiliCam: Using Mobile Phones to Monitor Newborn Jaundice*. ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing (UbiComp) 2014 *Best paper nominee*

Boulanger, C., Boulanger, A., **de Greef, L.**, Kearney, A., Sobel, K., Transue, R., Sweedyk, Z., Dietz, P., Bathiche, S. *Stroke Rehabilitation with a Sensing Surface*. 2013 ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Proceedings (CHI) 2013

Berezny, N., **de Greef, L.**, Jensen, B., Sheely, K., Sok, M., Lingenbrink, D., Dodds, Z. *Accessible Aerial Autonomy.* IEEE International Conference on Technologies for Practical Robot Applications (TePRA) 2012

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research, University of Washington

9/2012 - present

Advisor: Shwetak Patel

Currently investigating how to use smartphone cameras to screen newborns for dangerous levels of jaundice, or yellowing of the skin, in close collaboration with UW Medical Center. Developed data collection procedures and software, applying computer vision to parse images, and using machine learning to estimate jaundice levels. Thus far in two publications, two patents, commercial development.

Research Intern, Microsoft Research Redmond

6/2015 - 9/2015

Manager: Merrie Morris

Conceived and developed a prototype of TeleTourist, a system that uses video calls with strangers to share experiences for people with mobility restrictions. Interviewed individuals with mobility restrictions as formative work, designed system features, and implemented a subset of them for a prototype. Presented the work as a poster at CSCW 2016 and resulted in a patent.

Research Science Intern, Amazon

6/2014 - 9/2014

Manager: Jim Curlander

Designed, developed, and evaluated eyes and head tracking based user interface elements for enhanced reality interfaces in fulfillment centers. Combined concepts from computer graphics with HCI Produced several prototypes, demonstrated the system in its intended environment. Resulted in a patent.

Microsoft Computer Science Clinic, Harvey Mudd College

9/2011 – 5/2012

Faculty Advisor: Z Sweedyk Microsoft Liaison: Cati Boulanger

Designed and developed technology to motivate and assess rehabilitation for stroke patients affected in their upper extremities, using the Microsoft Surface in team of four. Interviewed stroke patients and physical therapists, designed a rehabilitative game played on the Microsoft Surface, produced a prototype, and ran user study with stroke patients.

Undergraduate Research, Harvey Mudd College

6/2011 – 8/2011

Advisor: Zachary Dodds

Created and explored vision-based localization algorithms for aerial robots, in team of five students. Prototyped autonomous cooperation between ground-based and airborne robots. Demonstrated localization for a quadrotor helicopter toy using only a built-in camera.

PATENTS

Colburn, R.A., Curlander, J.C., Gorumkonda, G.K., de Greef, L., inventors; Aug. 2017. **Perspective-Aware Projected User Interfaces**. United States patent US 9723248 B1.

Quinn, K.I., Morris, M., Venolia, G., Tang, J., de Greef, L., inventors; Mar. 2017. **Immersive Telepresence**. United States patent US 9591260 B1.

Taylor, J.A., Patel, S.N., Stout, J.W., de Greef, L., Goel, M., Larson, E.C., inventors; Dec. 2015. **Systems, Devices, and Methods for Estimating Bilirubin Levels**. United States patent US 20150359459 A1.

Taylor, J.A., Patel, S.N., Stout, J.W., de Greef, L., Goel, M., Larson, E.C., inventors; Oct. 2014. **Estimating Bilirubin Levels**. United States patent US WO2014172033 A1.

SKILLS

Programming: Python, C++, OpenCV, Java, Arduino, SystemVerilog, Objective-C , C#, Scheme, Prolog Software: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, Photoshop, Autodesk 3DS Max

Hardware: 3D printing, laser cutting, eTextiles fabrication, machining for metal and wood

TALKS

BiliCam: Using Mobile Phones to Monitor Newborn Jaundice. ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing (UbiComp), Seattle, WA, 16 September 2014

Using Mobile Technology to Monitor Bilirubin and Diagnose Jaundice in Infants. Global WACh Seminar Series, Seattle, WA, 12 February 2014 (Invited Speaker)

Ubiquitous Computing: Our Approach to Technology Innovations. Northwest Regional Women in Computing (NWrWIC), Portland, OR, 19 October 2013 **(Distinguished Speaker)**

Stroke Rehabilitation with the Microsoft Surface. Harvey Mudd College Projects Day, Claremont, CA, 1 May 2012.

Microsoft Surface for Stroke Rehabilitation. Celebration of Women in Computing in Southern California (CWIC-SoCal), Santa Ana, CA, 14 April 2012.

Accessible Aerial Autonomy. Celebration of Women in Computing in Southern California (CWIC-SoCal), Santa Ana, CA, 14 April 2012.

Accessible Aerial Autonomy. Harvey Mudd College Computer Science Colloquium, Claremont, CA, 8 September 2011

LogiSketch: An Intuitive System for Sketching and Simulating Logic Circuits. Harvey Mudd College Computer Science Colloquium, Claremont, CA, 21 October 2010

DEMONSTRATIONS

Berezny, N., **de Greef, L.**, Jensen, B., Sheely, K., Sok, M., Dodds, Z. *Accessible Aerial Autonomy via ROS*. Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), San Francisco, CA, June 2011

Berezny, N., **de Greef, L.**, Jensen, B., Sheely, K., Sok, M., Dodds, Z. *Autonomous Robot Cooperation*. Global Conference on Educational Robotics (GCER), Orange County, CA, July 2011

SERVICE

| K-12 Outreach, University of Washington Open House, Tours, Demos | 2012 - present |
|--|------------------|
| Student Volunteer, UbiComp Conference | 2013, 2014, 2015 |
| Graduate Student Co-Coordinator, University of Washington CSE | 2013 – 2015 |
| Alumni Interviewer, Harvey Mudd College Admissions Office | 2012 – 2014 |
| Role Model & Mentor, she++ | 2012 – 2013 |
| Mentor, WitsOn (Women in Technology Sharing Online) | 2012 – 2013 |